I'm driven by pure passion
مدفوعاَ بشغف نقي
to create photographs that tell stories.
لابتكار صور تحكي قصصاَ.
Photography can be described as the recording of a single moment
يمكن وصف التصوير الفوتوغرافي على أنه تسجيل للحظة واحدة
frozen within a fraction of time.
مجمدة في جزءٍ من الوقت.
Each moment or photograph represents a tangible piece
تمثلُ كل لحظة أو صورة قطعة حقيقية ملموسة
of our memories as time passes.
من ذكرياتنا مع مرور الوقت.
But what if you could capture more than one moment in a photograph?
ولكن ماذا لو تمكنت من تصوير أكثر من لحظة واحدة في صورة؟
What if a photograph could actually collapse time,
ماذا لو كان بإمكان الصورة دمج الوقت،
compressing the best moments of the day and the night
وجمع أفضل لحظات النهار و الليل
seamlessly into one single image?
بدون ندوب في صورة واحدة؟
I've created a concept called "Day to Night"
لقد أنشأت مفهموماَ يُدعى "من النهار إلى الليل"
and I believe it's going to change
و أظن أنه سيغير
the way you look at the world.
طريقة نظرتكم إلى العالم.
I know it has for me.
كما فعلت معي.
My process begins by photographing iconic locations,
بدأت طريقتي بتصوير مواقع ذات دلالة تذكارية،
places that are part of what I call our collective memory.
أماكن هي أجزاء من ما أسميه ذاكرتنا الجماعية.
I photograph from a fixed vantage point, and I never move.
أصور من أفضل نقطة نظر ثابتة ولا أتحرك أبداً.
I capture the fleeting moments of humanity and light as time passes.
أصور لحظات عابرة من النشاط البشري والضوء مع مرور الوقت.
Photographing for anywhere from 15 to 30 hours
التصوير في أي مكانِ لمدة تترواح بين 15 إلى 30 ساعة
and shooting over 1,500 images,
والتقاط أكثر من 1،500 صورة،
I then choose the best moments of the day and night.
وأختارُ بعد ذلك أفضل اللحظات من النهار والليل.
Using time as a guide,
مستخدماَ الوقت كدليل،
I seamlessly blend those best moments into one single photograph,
أقوم بمزج أفضل اللقطات بسلاسة في صورةٍ منفردة واحدة،
visualizing our conscious journey with time.
مصوراَ رحلة إدراكنا للوقت.
I can take you to Paris
يمكنني أخذكم إلى باريس
for a view from the Tournelle Bridge.
لمشهد من على جسر التورنيل.
And I can show you the early morning rowers
و أستطيع أن أريكم المجدفين في الصباح الباكر
along the River Seine.
على طول نهر السين.
And simultaneously,
وفي وقتٍ واحد،
I can show you Notre Dame aglow at night.
أستطيع أن أريكم كاتدرائية نوتردام المتوهجة في الليل.
And in between, I can show you the romance of the City of Light.
وخلال ذلك، سأريكم رومانسية مدينة النور.
I am essentially a street photographer from 50 feet in the air,
أنا في الأساس مصور الشارع من ارتفاع 50 قدماَ في الهواء،
and every single thing you see in this photograph
وكل شيء ترونه في هذه الصورة
actually happened on this day.
حدث فعلاَ في هذا اليوم.
Day to Night is a global project,
من النهار إلى الليل هو مشروع عالمي،
and my work has always been about history.
وكان عملي دائماَ عن التاريخ.
I'm fascinated by the concept of going to a place like Venice
أنا مفتون بفكرة الذهاب إلى مكان مثل البندقية
and actually seeing it during a specific event.
و رؤيتها في الواقع خلال حدث معين.
And I decided I wanted to see the historical Regata,
وقررت رؤية سباق القوارب التاريخية،
an event that's actually been taking place since 1498.
وهو الحدث الذي يُقام في الواقع منذ عام 1498.
The boats and the costumes look exactly as they did then.
تبدو القوارب و الأزياء تماماَ كما كانت عليه في ذلك الوقت.
And an important element that I really want you guys to understand is:
و العنصر المهم الذي أريدكم يا أصدقاء أن تفهموه هو:
this is not a timelapse,
ليست هذه لقطات متتابعة،
this is me photographing throughout the day and the night.
هذا أنا أصور طوال النهار والليل.
I am a relentless collector of magical moments.
أجمعُ بمثابرة اللحظات السحرية.
And the thing that drives me is the fear of just missing one of them.
و الشيء الذي يدفعني هو فقط الخوف من ضياع أحدها.
The entire concept came about in 1996.
أتى المفهوم بالكامل إلى حيز الوجود في عام 1996.
LIFE Magazine commissioned me to create a panoramic photograph
عندما كلفتني "مجلة لايف" بتنفيذ صورة بانوارامية
of the cast and crew of Baz Luhrmann's film Romeo + Juliet.
لشخصيات و طاقم فيلم روميو وجولييت للمخرج السينمائي باز لورمان.
I got to the set and realized: it's a square.
التقطتُ مجموعة من الصور وأدركتُ أنها على شكل مربع.
So the only way I could actually create a panoramic was to shoot a collage
لذلك فالطريقة الوحيدة لصنع صورة بانورامية كان تكوين قص ولصق الصور
of 250 single images.
من 250 صورة منفصلة.
So I had DiCaprio and Claire Danes embracing.
كان دي كابريو و كلير دينز يتعانقان.
And as I pan my camera to the right,
وعندما أدرتُ كاميرتي إلى اليمين،
I noticed there was a mirror on the wall
لاحظت وجود مرآة على الجدار
and I saw they were actually reflecting in it.
ورأيتُ انعكاس صورتيهما في الحقيقة.
And for that one moment, that one image
و من أجل تلك اللحظة، وتلك الصورة
I asked them, "Would you guys just kiss
طلبتُ منهما ، "هلا قبلتما بعضكما
for this one picture?"
لهذه الصورة؟
And then I came back to my studio in New York,
و عدتُ بعدها إلى الاستوديو الخاص بي في نيويورك،
and I hand-glued these 250 images together
و لصقت تلك الصور ال 250 مع بعض
and stood back and went, "Wow, this is so cool!
وقفت في الخلف وقلت، "جميل، هذا رائع جداَ!
I'm changing time in a photograph."
أنا أغير الوقت في صورة."
And that concept actually stayed with me for 13 years
و استمر المفهوم معي لمدة 13 عاما
until technology finally has caught up to my dreams.
حتى أدركت التكنولوجيا أحلامي أخيراَ.
This is an image I created of the Santa Monica Pier, Day to Night.
هذه صورة أنشأتها لميناء سانتا مونيكا، بمبدأ اليوم لليل،
And I'm going to show you a little video
و سأريكم شريطا صغيرا
that gives you an idea of what it's like being with me
يعطيكم فكرة عن الذي يجري معي
when I do these pictures.
عندما أصور هذه الصور.
To start with, you have to understand that to get views like this,
في البداية، يجب أن ندرك أنه للحصول على إطلالة كهذه،
most of my time is spent up high, and I'm usually in a cherry picker
قضيت معظم وقتي فوق في الأعلى، وعادة في الحاملة المرتفعة
or a crane.
أو الرافعة.
So this is a typical day, 12-18 hours, non-stop
لذلك هذا هو يوم عادي، 12-18 ساعة ،بدون توقف
capturing the entire day unfold.
نلتقط صوراَ في اليوم بكامله .
One of the things that's great is I love to people-watch.
أحد الأشياء العظيمة هي أنني أحب مشاهدة الناس.
And trust me when I tell you,
و ثقوا في عندما أخبركم،
this is the greatest seat in the house to have.
هذا هو أعظم مقعد يمكن أن تملكه في المكان،
But this is really how I go about creating these photographs.
ولكن هذا فعلياَ ما أقوم به لأخذ هذه الصور.
So once I decide on my view and the location,
لذلك و بمجرد أن أختار إطلالتي و الموقع،
I have to decide where day begins and night ends.
لا بد أن أقرر أين سيبدأ اليوم وأين ينتهي الليل.
And that's what I call the time vector.
وهذا ما أطلق عليه عامل الزمن.
Einstein described time as a fabric.
وقد وصف آينشتاين الوقت كالقماش.
Think of the surface of a trampoline:
لنفكر في سطح الترامبولين:
it warps and stretches with gravity.
إنه يلتف و يتمدد مع الجاذبية.
I see time as a fabric as well,
أنا أرى الزمن كالقماش أيضاَ،
except I take that fabric and flatten it, compress it into single plane.
إلا أنني آخذ النسيج و أسطحه،وأضغطه في مستوى واحد.
One of the unique aspects of this work is also,
أحد الجوانب الفريدة في هذا العمل أيضاَ،
if you look at all my pictures,
إذا نظرتم إلى كل صوري،
the time vector changes:
عامل الزمن يتغير:
sometimes I'll go left to right,
أحياناَ أذهب من اليسار لليمين،
sometimes front to back, up or down, even diagonally.
أحياناَ من الأمام إلى الخلف، من الأعلى أو الأسفل، حتى قطرياَ.
I am exploring the space-time continuum
أنا أستكشف استمرارية الزمان المكاني
within a two-dimensional still photograph.
داخل صورة ثابتة ثنائية الأبعاد.
Now when I do these pictures,
الآن عندما أصمم هذه الصور،
it's literally like a real-time puzzle going on in my mind.
ستكون تماماَ مثل لغز الوقت الحقيقي وهو يدور في ذهني.
I build a photograph based on time,
أصنع صورة تستند على الوقت،
and this is what I call the master plate.
وهذا هو ما أسميه لوحة رئيسية.
This can take us several months to complete.
وهذه قد تأخذ أشهرا عديدة لتكتمل.
The fun thing about this work is
الشيء الممتع في هذا العمل
I have absolutely zero control when I get up there
ولن تكون لي أي سيطرة عندما أكون هناك في الأعلى
on any given day and capture photographs.
في يومٍ ما لإلتقاط الصور الفوتوغرافية .
So I never know who's going to be in the picture,
لذلك لا أعرف من سيكون في الصورة،
if it's going to be a great sunrise or sunset -- no control.
فيما إذا كان شروقاَ أو غروباَ عظيماَ--لا سيطرة.
It's at the end of the process,
إنما تتم في نهاية هذه العملية،
if I've had a really great day and everything remained the same,
إذا كان يوماَ عظيماَ حقاَ و بقي كل شيء على حاله،
that I then decide who's in and who's out,
عندها سأقرر من سيبقى ومن سيخرج،
and it's all based on time.
وكله يعتمد على الوقت فقط.
I'll take those best moments that I pick over a month of editing
سآخذ أفضل اللحظات التي التقطت في أكثر من شهر من التحرير
and they get seamlessly blended into the master plate.
ويتم مزجها بسلاسة لتكون اللوحة الرئيسية.
I'm compressing the day and night
أضغط الليل و النهار
as I saw it,
كما شاهدته،
creating a unique harmony between these two very discordant worlds.
مبدعا تناغماَ فريداَ بين هذين العالمين المتنافرين.
Painting has always been a really important influence in all my work
كان لفن الرسم دائماَ تأثير مهم في جميع أعمالي
and I've always been a huge fan of Albert Bierstadt,
ولقد كنت دائما من المعجبين بألبرت بيرشدات،
the great Hudson River School painter.
الرسام العظيم للوحة مدرسة نهر هدسون.
He inspired a recent series that I did on the National Parks.
ألهمني في السلسلة الأخيرة التي قمت بها في المتنزهات الوطنية.
This is Bierstadt's Yosemite Valley.
هذه لوحة وادي يوسمايت لبيرشدات.
So this is the photograph I created of Yosemite.
و تلك الصورة التي اخذتها ليوسمايت.
This is actually the cover story of the 2016 January issue
هذا عنوان الغلاف لإصدار يناير 2016
of National Geographic.
من ناشيونال جيوغرافيك.
I photographed for over 30 hours in this picture.
صورت لأكثر من 30 ساعة من أجل تكوين هذه الصورة.
I was literally on the side of a cliff,
كنت فعلياَ على جانبٍ منحدر،
capturing the stars and the moonlight as it transitions,
ملتقطاَ النجوم و ضوء القمر بتبدلاته،
the moonlight lighting El Capitan.
ضوء القمر ينيرمنحدر إل كابيتان.
And I also captured this transition of time throughout the landscape.
و التقطت أيضاَ تحول الوقت في جميع أجزاء المشهد.
The best part is obviously seeing the magical moments of humanity
أفضل جزء كان بالتأكيد رؤية اللحظات السحرية للإنسانية
as time changed --
مع تغير الوقت--
from day into night.
من النهار إلى الليل.
And on a personal note,
وعلى صعيد شخصي،
I actually had a photocopy of Bierstadt's painting in my pocket.
كان عندي نسخة للوحة بيرشتاد في جيبي.
And when that sun started to rise in the valley,
و عندما بدأت الشمس بالسطوع في الوادي،
I started to literally shake with excitement
بدأت حرفياَ بالإرتعاش من التأثر
because I looked at the painting and I go,
لأنني أنظر للوحة و أردد،
"Oh my god, I'm getting Bierstadt's exact same lighting
"يا إلهي، أنا أحصل على نفس إضاءة لوحة بيرشتاد
100 years earlier."
قبل 100 سنة مضت."
Day to Night is about all the things,
النهار لليل هو كل الأشياء،
it's like a compilation of all the things I love
إنه مثل تجميع كل الأشياء التي أحبها
about the medium of photography.
عن وسيلة للتصوير الفوتوغرافي.
It's about landscape,
هي المشهد،
it's about street photography,
هي التصوير في الشارع،
it's about color, it's about architecture,
هي اللون،هي الفن المعماري،
perspective, scale -- and, especially, history.
المنظور و النطاق -- و خصوصاَ التاريخ.
This is one of the most historical moments
هذه أحد أكثر اللحظات تاريخيةَ
I've been able to photograph,
التي تمكنت من تصويرها،
the 2013 Presidential Inauguration of Barack Obama.
تنصيب الرئيس باراك أوباما في عام 2013.
And if you look closely in this picture,
وإذا نظرت عن كثب في هذه الصورة،
you can actually see time changing
ستتمكن فعلاَ من رؤية تغير الزمن
in those large television sets.
في تلك الأجهزة التلفزيونية الكبيرة.
You can see Michelle waiting with the children,
ستشاهد ميشيل تنتظر مع الأولاد،
the president now greets the crowd,
و الآن الرئيس يحيي الحشود،
he takes his oath,
ثم يؤدي القسم ،
and now he's speaking to the people.
والآن يتحدث مع الناس.
There's so many challenging aspects when I create photographs like this.
هناك الكثير من جوانب التحدي عندما أقوم بأخذ صور من هذا القبيل.
For this particular photograph,
في هذه الصورة خاصةَ،
I was in a 50-foot scissor lift up in the air
كنت في رافعة معدنية في الأعلى بارتفاع 50 قدما في الهواء
and it was not very stable.
ولم تكن مستقرة تماما،
So every time my assistant and I shifted our weight,
لذلك كلما كنا أنا ومساعدي نحرك أوزاننا،
our horizon line shifted.
يتحرك خط الأفق بالنسبة لنا.
So for every picture you see,
لذلك في كل صورة تشاهدونها،
and there were about 1,800 in this picture,
وكان هناك حوالي 1800 لقطة في هذه الصورة،
we both had to tape our feet into position
كان علينا أن نلصق أقدامنا بالشريط في مكاننا
every time I clicked the shutter.
في كل مرة أضغظ فيها على غالق الكاميرا.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
I've learned so many extraordinary things doing this work.
لقد تعلمت الكثير من الأشياء الاستثنائية في القيام بهذا العمل.
I think the two most important are patience
أظن أن أهم شيئين هما الصبر
and the power of observation.
و قوة الملاحظة.
When you photograph a city like New York from above,
عند تصوير مدينة مثل نيويورك من الأعلى،
I discovered that those people in cars
اكتشفت أن هؤلاء الناس في السيارات
that I sort of live with everyday,
والذين أعييش معهم نوعا ما يومياَ،
they don't look like people in cars anymore.
لا يبدون كالناس في السيارات على الإطلاق.
They feel like a giant school of fish,
يبدون كقطيع هائل من الأسماك،
it was a form of emergent behavior.
كان شكلاَ من أشكال السلوك الناشئ.
And when people describe the energy of New York,
وعندما يصف الناس طاقة نيويورك،
I think this photograph begins to really capture that.
أظن هذه الصورة تبدأ فعلياَ بإظهار ذلك.
When you look closer in my work,
عندما تنظر عن كثب في أعمالي،
you can see there's stories going on.
سترى قصصاَ تجري.
You realize that Times Square is a canyon,
ستدرك أن تايمز سكوير هي واد عميق،
it's shadow and it's sunlight.
هي عبارة عن ظل و عن ضوء النهار.
So I decided, in this photograph, I would checkerboard time.
لذلك قررت أن أجعل الوقت كمربعات الشطرنج في هذه الصورة.
So wherever the shadows are, it's night
لذلك أينماَ يكون مكان الظل، سيكون الليل
and wherever the sun is, it's actually day.
وفي المكان المشمس، فهو في الواقع النهار.
Time is this extraordinary thing
الوقت هو ذلك الشيء غير العادي
that we never can really wrap our heads around.
والذي لا نستطيع أن نلتف برؤوسنا حوله.
But in a very unique and special way,
ولكن بطريقة فريدة جداَ وخاصة،
I believe these photographs begin to put a face on time.
أعتقد أن هذه الصور بدأت تضع للوقت وجها.
They embody a new metaphysical visual reality.
أنها تجسد واقعاَ مرئياَ خارقاَ وجديداَ.
When you spend 15 hours looking at a place,
عندما تمضي 15 ساعة بالتأمل تنظر إلى مكان ما،
you're going to see things a little differently
ستبدأ بمشاهدة الأشياء بطريقة مختلفة قليلاَ
than if you or I walked up with our camera,
أكثر مما لو مشينا مع الكاميرا،
took a picture, and then walked away.
وأخذنا صورة، و مضينا بعيدا.
This was a perfect example.
وهذا كان خير مثال.
I call it "Sacré-Coeur Selfie."
أسميها "سيلفي القلب الأقدس."
I watched over 15 hours
شاهدت لأكثر من 15 ساعة
all these people not even look at Sacré-Coeur.
كل هؤلاء الناس لم ينظروا حتى لكنيسة القلب المقدس.
They were more interested in using it as a backdrop.
كانوا أكثر اهتماماَ في استخدامها كخلفية.
They would walk up, take a picture,
يودون المشي،أخذ صورة،
and then walk away.
ثم المغادرة.
And I found this to be an absolutely extraordinary example,
ولقد وجدت هذا أكثر مثال استثنائيةَ على الإطلاق،
a powerful disconnect between what we think the human experience is
إنفصال قوي بين أفكارنا عن التجربة الإنسانية
versus what the human experience is evolving into.
مقابل ما تتطور فيه التجربة الإنسانية.
The act of sharing has suddenly become more important
القيام بالمشاركة أصبح فجأةَ أكثر أهمية
than the experience itself.
من التجربة نفسها.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
And finally, my most recent image,
وأخيراَ،صورتي الأحدث،
which has such a special meaning for me personally:
والتي تحمل معنى خاصا لي شخصياَ:
this is the Serengeti National Park in Tanzania.
هذه حديقة سيرينجيتي الوطنية في تنزانيا.
And this is photographed in the middle of the Seronera,
وهذه صورت في وسط سيرونيرا،
this is not a reserve.
هذه ليست محمية.
I went specifically during the peak migration
ذهبت في فترة ذروة الهجرة تحديداَ
to hopefully capture the most diverse range of animals.
أملاَ في تصوير أكبر مجموعة متنوعة من الحيوانات.
Unfortunately, when we got there,
للأسف، عندما وصلنا إلى هناك،
there was a drought going on during the peak migration,
كان هناك جفاف مستمر في فترة ذروة الهجرة،
a five-week drought.
خمسة أسابيع من الجفاف.
So all the animals were drawn to the water.
لذلك انجذبت كل الحيوانات إلى الماء.
I found this one watering hole,
وجدت حفرة الماء هذه،
and felt if everything remained the same way it was behaving,
وشعرت إذا بقي كل شيء بنفس الطريقة التي يحدث بها،
I had a real opportunity to capture something unique.
كان عندي فرصة حقيقية لالتقاط شيء فريد من نوعه.
We spent three days studying it,
قضينا ثلاثة أيام على دراسته،
and nothing could have prepared me
ولم يكن هناك ما يهيؤني
for what I witnessed during our shoot day.
لما شهدته خلال يوم التصوير هناك.
I photographed for 26 hours
صورت لمدة 26 ساعة
in a sealed crocodile blind, 18 feet in the air.
مختفيا في مخبأ تمساح بارتفاع 18 قدماَ في الهواء.
What I witnessed was unimaginable.
ما شاهدته لا يمكن تصوره.
Frankly, it was Biblical.
بصراحة، كان مقدساَ.
We saw, for 26 hours,
شاهدنا، لمدة 26 ساعة،
all these competitive species share a single resource called water.
كل هذه الأنواع المتنافسة تتشارك مورداَ واحداَ يدعى الماء.
The same resource that humanity is supposed to have wars over
نفس المورد الذي من المفترض أن تخوض الإنسانية حروباَ من أجله
during the next 50 years.
خلال ال50 عاماَ القادمة.
The animals never even grunted at each other.
لم تزمجر الحيوانات على بعضها من أجله.
They seem to understand something that we humans don't.
بدوا و كأنهم فهموا شيئاَ لا نفهمه نحن البشر.
That this precious resource called water
أن هذا المورد الثمين المدعو بالماء
is something we all have to share.
شيء يجب أن نتشارك فيه جميعاَ.
When I created this picture,
عندما التقطت هذه الصورة،
I realized that Day to Night is really a new way of seeing,
أدركت أن النهار لليل هو حقا وسيلة جديدة للرؤية،
compressing time,
وضغط الوقت،
exploring the space-time continuum within a photograph.
واستكشاف استمرارية الزمان المكاني في صورة.
As technology evolves along with photography,
وبما أن التكنولوجيا تتطور مع التصوير،
photographs will not only communicate a deeper meaning of time and memory,
فلن تنقل الصورفقط معنى أعمق عن الوقت والذاكرة،
but they will compose a new narrative of untold stories,
لكنها ستؤلف سرداَ جديداَ من القصص التي لا تعد ولا تحصى،
creating a timeless window into our world.
خالقة نافذة خالدة إلى عالمنا.
Thank you.
شكراَ.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)